Well, that was a sneaky detour I took you on in the last one.
지난번엔 내가 좀 엉뚱하게 둘러갔죠
I hope you enjoyed it though, and I hope you found it satisfying and that you're playing around with
그래도 즐거우셨길 바라요 만족스러우셨길 바라고 이번 주를 즐기셨길
that week.
바라요
4.5 day 4.5 right now.
4살요 5일째, 4일째예요 지금은 5시예요
But back to the main plan, which was that we were going to talk about Lang chain expression language,
본론으로 돌아가서 랭 체인 표현 언어를 얘기하려고 했는데요 랭 체인에서
which is the way that you can set up your chains in Lang chain, which is how Lang Chain thinks about
체인을 설정하는 방법입니다 랭 체인은 파이프라인을 풀기 위해 퍼즐의
the different steps in the puzzle that are glued together to solve your pipeline.
여러 단계를 어떻게 풀었는지를 뜻하죠
And you can do that by putting together a file that expresses, in a declarative style what it is that
여러분이 이루고자 하는 것을 표현해주는 파일을 함께 놓을
you're looking to achieve.
수 있어요.
So this LCL lang chain expression language can be used to lay out what you want to do.
이 LCL lang 체인 표현 언어는 여러분이 원하는 걸 레이아웃하는 데 사용될 수 있어요
It's in the form of a YAML file.
YAML 파일 형태예요
If you're familiar with YAML files and it looks like this.
YAML 파일에 익숙하신 분들을 위해 설명드리죠
And if we look if we read through this, you can see that we've got here we're specifying a model with
이걸 읽어보면 온도를 가진 모델을 지정하고 있는 게 보이실 겁니다
a temperature with a directory that, that um, that will be the persistent directory for our vector
디렉터리와 관련해서요 벡터 데이터베이스의 영구 디렉터리죠
And then we have these different components the LM which is of type chat, open AI.
그리고 다양한 구성 요소가 있죠 LM은 형식 채팅, 열린 인공지능이에요
We have the conversation memory.
대화 메모리가 있어요
We have the open AI embeddings, the chroma vector store, the retriever and the chain and the output.
열린 인공지능 내장 크로마 벡터 스토어 회수기와 체인, 출력도요
So hopefully you see how this maps very closely indeed to the Python code that we wrote.
우리가 작성한 파이썬 코드와 아주 밀접하게 매핑되어 있죠
And you can imagine that these kinds of declarative models can be put together to solve all sorts of
이런 선언적 모델이 한데 합쳐져 모든 문제를 해결할 수 있다고 상상해 보세요. TUI
problems.
함께 시간을 보낸 사람들이 만든 아주 강력한 언어예요
I think it's it's very productive at this point.
지금은 아주 생산적인 것 같아요
My personal preference is to stick with Python code and use that to put this together, to put together
저는 개인적으로 파이썬 코드를 선호합니다. 그리고 그것을 이용해서 이전에 했던 워크플로를
our workflows as we did before.
함께 만드는 것을 선호해요.
But if this interests you, you could look more at this and consider this as an alternative.
하지만 이게 관심 있다면 이걸 좀 더 보고 대안으로 생각해도 돼요
And if you come across this in some other project, you hopefully won't be perturbed by it.
다른 프로젝트에서 이걸 발견해도 동요하지 않으셨으면 해요
It maps pretty closely to the Python code, so the next thing I wanted to do was just talk a little
파이썬 코드와 아주 밀접하게 매핑됩니다 다음으로 살펴볼 내용은 랭 체인이 어떻게
bit about how Lang Chain works behind the scenes, but hopefully at this point you've got a pretty good
비트에서 작동하는지에 대한 것입니다 이미 직관적으로 잘 이해하셨기를
intuition into that already.
바라면서요
Uh Langshan isn't doing a ton of magic.
랑산은 술법이 약해요
It's just very convenient indeed.
정말 편리한 방법이죠
But really, it is just making the right calls to the different underlying components like chroma or
사실 크로마나 Feis 같은 기본 구성 요소에 올바른 호출을 하는
Feis.
거죠
It's retrieving the right, uh, documents, and then it is stitching them into the prompt.
올바른 문서를 검색해 프롬프트에 꿰매는 거죠
So I'm going to show you in a second how we can use things called callbacks to get langshan to tell
잠시 후에 보여드릴 건 콜백이라는 걸 어떻게 이용하느냐예요 랑산 박사에게
us what actually was the prompt that it is sending to OpenAI.
오픈AI에 보내는 프롬프트가 뭔지 알아내는 거죠
At the end of the day, after it's done this lookup, and we can use that to diagnose a common problem
결국 조사가 끝난 후 공통적인 문제를 진단하는 데 사용할 수 있어요
that happens, which is what happens if, for whatever reason, the right chunks aren't sent to the
어떤 이유에서든 올바른 덩어리가 모델로 보내지 않았거나 적어도 우리가 정말 원하는 덩어리가
to the model, or at least not the chunk that we really wanted, so that it doesn't provide us with
아닐 경우 발생하죠 우리가 원하는 종류의 답을 제공하지
the kind of answer we wanted.
않는 거예요
Well, then fix that problem, and we'll end with some thoughts on just demystifying the whole, uh,
그럼 그 문제를 해결하고 랭산의 인프라 구조를 이해하기
infrastructure that Langshan provides us.
쉽게 마무리하죠
And with that, we'll head back to JupyterLab for the real day five this time.
이것과 함께 주피터랩으로 돌아가 진짜 5일째를 살펴보죠 HDMI HDMI